# **Anas Amin**

Working as a full-stack Software Engineer for the past 7 years mostly on web applications and covering the entire stack. My experience spans multiple web development platforms and that has honed my self-learning skill and in the recent years my interest towards working on AWS and other cloud services has fostered.

B-104, Gate 3, PIA Society Block 9, Johar, Karachi +923152908926 m.anas.amin@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### FAIR Consultancy Group, Karachi - Consultant

July 2020 - Present

I am responsible for providing software architectural cloud consultancy for on-going projects at FAIR CG. My current area of focus is AWS and I am preparing for AWS certifications in my current role as well..

### KASB, Karachi - Development Team Lead

MARCH 2020 - July 2020

I was responsible for laying the groundwork for a container-based solution that was being developed for Jazz Cash and mentored the development team. My responsibility included ensuring the integrity of the architecture and conform to client requirements during the development process.

# Auriga Solutions, Karachi - Senior Software Engineer

MARCH 2016 - PRESENT

The longest job I have held to date and for good reasons. I am exposed to building, optimizing, and supporting modules in live applications for an offshore insurance client.

# GoodCore Software, Karachi — Software Engineer

**JULY 2014 - MARCH 2016** 

My first job as a Software Engineer. Worked here as a Web Developer on a number of platforms, namely, Ruby on Rails, Java EE, and Yii framework for php.

### **PROJECTS**

# **AWS Control Tower Accelerator** – *AWS Control Tower, AWS CloudFormation*

This was a research based project that I am doing at FAIR Consultancy. The reason for taking on this project is to introduce account management and accountability in our internal projects. The project is also meant to be used as an accelerator that the company can sold to potential clients.

# Jazz Cash Stock Trading Module - AWS ECS, .NET Core, Microservices, DynamoDB

This was a microservice based trading module that was being developed for Jazz Cash application. The core areas that I worked on during this

#### **SKILLS**

- C#, Vue.js
- AWS, Fargate, ECS
- Serverless
   Architecture, AWS API
   Gateway, AWS
   Websocket API
- DynamoDB
- AWS Control Tower
- MVC
- SQL Server, Elastic Search
- Software Architecture
- Javascript

### **WORKPLACE INITIATIVES**

- Took the initiative of researching and making a POC for a serverless application using AWS Lambda and Step Functions
- Led the effort on developing unit test cases using Moq and Bogus for MVC applications and Web API
- Played an active role in migration of certain backend modules from SQL to ElasticSearch

#### **VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE**

project was introducing best practices for working on microservice applications and mentoring the team

# **Redstone JobBoard** - *Vue JS, AWS Serverless Architecture, .NET Core*

RedStone JobBoard is a custom ERP for Redstone Print and Mail. JobBoard application is a real time application that lives in the browser and updates its state via the websocket API.

# **Redstone Streetview** - *Vue JS*, *AWS Serverless Architecture*, .NET Core

RedStone Streetview is a SaaS address file processor, it takes in a massive address file and outputs an archive containing the images of the addresses using Google Streetview API. Other client apps can also utilize the service on the basis of a tailored subscription plan.

## **MACTool 2.0** - Angular 4, MVC .NET, Elastic Search

MACTool 2.0 was created for another insurance clients using Angular 4 and ElasticSearch. The tools allows the users to manage their insurance leads by providing various visual and management tools.

## Planet Altig Desktop - Universal Windows Platform

Altig, an insurance company based in US wanted to port their older Windows application to Windows 10 devices.

This application was developed in Universal Windows Platform And is currently available for Windows 10 app store.

### **MACTool 1.0** - AngularJS, MVC .net, Elastic Search

Altig, an insurance company based in US wanted to extend their online portal by adding a single page module in their existing portal.

This module was developed in AngularJS with ElasticSearch at the backend. It basically shows their data on a google map and lets the user search and assign the data to various insurance agents.

# **DNSToolbox** — Ruby on Rails

MYNIC, a Malaysian based domain name seller, wanted to centralize their DNS Server configurational application. This application was used to configure DNS Servers (running BIND), with a limitation of having to install the application on the DNS Server the user wanted to configure.

I worked on centralizing this application, meaning that the application will be installed on the application server, and user can configure their DNS Servers remotely. SSH was the key dependency in this project.

# **DNSToolbox 2.0** — *Spring MVC*

DNSToolbox application lets an organization control and monitor their

- A part of Rahbar Program by TCF. The program connects school-going children from underprivileged areas to mentors for life advice and career counseling
- Participated in Career Counselling session by TCF

# EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES DURING BACHELOR'S

- Vice President of The Webmasters -2013-2014
- Executive Member of ACM-NUCES -2013-2014
- Content Manager of FAST-NUCES Karachi Web Portal, 2011 -2014

DNS systems using a web browser.

MYNIC wanted to provide DNSToolbox as a service to their clients. For this, they asked us to make DNSToolbox from scratch and on Java EE. This required us to make more user types, user levels, and providing a few more accessibility features.

I am working on the core (DNS Server configurational) part of this application.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **FAST-NUCES**, Karachi — MS in Data Science

AUGUST 2017 - MAY 2021

The program includes exposure to Machine Learning, Big Data Analysis, Statistics, and Data Science tools and techniques.

## **FAST-NUCES**, Karachi — *BS(CS)*

AUGUST 2010 - JUNE 2014

The program had a strong focus on Computer Science basics and Programming